DYLAN WOOD

WEB ENGINEER

dylan.c.wood@gmail.com +1.505.480.5346 Portland, Oregon bydywo.blogspot.com

Profile

A curious engineer's mentality leads me to simplify and solve problems using the most practical tools available. Excited to expand upon 4 years of open-source web-dev experience through teamwork with excellent developers.

Skills

General

Productively utilize common open source tools across various environments to deliver and maintain web-based applications

Front End

Efficiently design, build and implement intuitive, responsive, maintainable and high-performance UIs in MVC style

Back End

Reliably develop and maintain server-side webservices, filesystems and databases, and the infrastructure on which they are deployed

Technical

Linux / OS X	CSS3	РНР
vim & eclipse	HTML(5)	Node.js
svn & git	JavaScript:jQuery[+ui + mobile]	SQL:[+Oracle +MySQL+Postgres]
GitHub	Phonegap/Cordova	OpsCode Chef

Experience

The Mind Research Network Neuroinformatics Group (coins.mrn.org)

Software Engineer II Jan 2010-Present

Co-Design, implement, maintain and extend medical research applications used at 7 institutions. Included the refactoring legacy code to use AJAX with RESTful webservices and MVC-model frameworks to deliver a rich UX. Successful products include:

Data Exchange: graphical, exploratory query builder for exploring and requesting complex multimodal data

Assessment Manager: questionnaire building and off-line collection system using HTML5 Local Storage API

Infrastructure: Migrate VMs to new physical hosts and oversee creation of Chef recipes

Dr. William Oberkampf

Matlab Programming Consultant Jan 2009-Jan 2010

Wrote, tested and modified scripts / functions for verification and validation examples used in the textbook "Verification and Validation in Scientific Computing"

The University Of New Mexico

Student Technical Expert Jun 2008-Jan 2010

Research assistant in the fields of Micro Electro-Mechanical Systems (MEMS). Projects included:

Designed and fabricated digital endoscope assembly for patent submission

Fabricated and analyzed micro structures and associated residual stresses

Designed and implemented 3in1 photolithography mask for micro-actuator fabrication

The University Of New Mexico

Computer Science Teaching Assistant Aug 2007 - Jan 2010

Created and instructed lab exercises for 17 students per week. Communicated with students to resolve conceptual misunderstandings.

Education

The University Of New Mexico, Albuquerque NM Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering 3.56/4.00 GPA Aug 2005-Dec 2009

Dylan Wood — dylan.c.wood@gmail.com — +1.505.480.5346